LEWIS CHAPMAN-BARKER

Contact number: 07973 851279 GitHub: https://github.com/lchapmb

Email: lchapmb@googlemail.com
 LinkedIn:

Location: Altrincham, Greater Manchester <u>www.linkedin.com/in/lewischapmanbarker</u>

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Software Developer with experience as an Account Executive who has recently completed a JavaScript bootcamp with training provider Northcoders, as well as a certificate in PHP from Codecademy. I am conscientious, used to working with clients in a professional context, and dedicated to continuous personal development.

I want to create technology which is both ethical and accessible; not just in the way it is used, but in ease of understanding. This allows both users and clients to make informed decisions about how they use this technology, and therefore to get the best use out of it.

SKILLS

JavaScript

Node

HTML/CSS

Express

Knex

SQL

Postgres

Jest

Supertest

EXPERIENCE

TRAINEE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER NORTHCODERS, MANCHESTER | 11/2020 - 03/2021

My time at Northcoders focused on software development using JavaScript, also covering principles such as pair-programming and test-driven development. Projects I have completed include:

Backend Project - a news site which uses Express and Postgres to make requests to a database of news articles, and tested using Jest and Supertest. The project is a work in progress, with more endpoints and functionality planned as it grows alongside the frontend site. Link to repo: https://github.com/lchapmb/be-nc-news Link to hosted site: https://nc-news-today.herokuapp.com/api

Frontend Project - a news site which React to display articles based on topic, as well as associated comments for each article. The site was designed mobile first, responsively, and with accessibility in mind. This will also soon include new CSS for larger view screens, and the ability for users to vote on articles and comments. Link to repo: https://github.com/lchapmb/nc-news

Final Project - working in a team of five, we created an order tracking app called Table Tracker, aimed at helping restaurants track order flow. In the backend, we used PostgreSQL to create a relational database which linked up to a React based frontend. We used Firebase Authentication for login, as well as implementing context and hooks for the first time. Our API was created using the Express JS web framework, following MVC architecture, and Knex JS for building queries. I'm hoping to develop the project further, now I have completed the bootcamp, including potentially hosting the project. Link to frontend repo:

https://github.com/lchapmb/Table-Tracker Link to backend repo: https://github.com/lchapmb/table-tracker-back-end

Portfolio - my portfolio site, built with vanilla HTML/CSS. Allows visitors to view contact information, my CV, and links to social media. Planned development includes more detailed project pages, and some tweaks to the styling. Link to repo:

https://github.com/lchapmb/lchapmb.github.io/ Link to hosted site: https://lchapmb.github.io/

CAREER BREAK | 01/2020 - 10/2020

I decided to take a career break in order to do some travelling, and to find out what I wanted to do next. It soon became clear that I would not be able to travel as extensively as planned due to the Covid-19 pandemic, and I started to explore online courses which may help my career.

This included completing the Responsive Web Design Certification on freeCodeCamp.org, and using Raspberry Pi micro-computers for projects like building a gaming emulator and a music player. I was inspired to spend more time on coding, and so began researching languages to learn. I decided to pursue JavaScript based on how in demand it was among employers, the accessibility of learning resources, and the variety of projects possible using the language. Northcoders in particular stood out as a training provider with an excellent track record in helping Junior Developers launch their career.

ACCOUNT EXECUTIVE

PRINT SEARCH LIMITED, TRAFFORD PARK | 07/2018 - 12/2019

- Primarily responsible for administrative and project support services for the Account Directors and Managers
- Prioritised projects, coordinating elements to ensure alignment with client schedules and critical shipment requests
- Assisting incoming call enquiries and customer orders, requiring in-depth knowledge of services and product availabilities
- Controlled stock inventory, arranging materials and supplies replenishments and deliveries
- Responsible for spearheading a new account, project-managed entire process from verifying orders to final production
- Assumed extended hours to honour project deadlines and won Employee of the Month for commitment and service

FUNDING & ONBOARDING EXECUTIVE

BPP UNIVERSITY, MANCHESTER | 05/2018 - 07/2018 - Temporary Role

RESOURCE PLANNING COORDINATOR

WELL PHARMACY, MANCHESTER | 02/2018 - 04/2018 - Temporary Role

REGIONAL SERVICE CONTROLLER

GLORY GLOBAL SOLUTIONS, ESSEX | 08/2016 - 12/2017 - Temporary Role

- Promoted to this role from original position of Call Closure & SLA Co-ordinator
- Initial remit focused on streamlining data-entry backlog and co-ordinating parts and materials aligned with project needs
- Managed personnel allocation, co-ordinating field engineers for deployment at planned and reactive maintenance tasks in the banking and retail sectors
- Co-ordinated project to upgrade nationwide estate of machines in advance of launch of new £5 note

REPORTER - INTERNSHIP

THE NUBIAN TIMES, MANCHESTER | 04/2016 - 06/2016

 Developed detailed understanding of fundamentals of editorial process and libel and copyright laws, sourcing content and actively pursuing story leads for publication

CLAIMS PROCESSOR

THE CLAIMS GUYS, ALTRINCHAM | 10/2015 - 04/2016

- Earned early promotion to this role within Financial Ombudsman team from original position of Data Entry Coordinator
- Managing application eligibility process following customers failed PPI claim referrals to the Ombudsman

RECEPTIONIST

INTERTEK, OLD TRAFFORD | 08/2015 - 10/2015 - Temporary Role

TRAINEE REPORTER

NEWS ASSOCIATES, MANCHESTER | 02/2015 - 07/2015 - Course

Diploma in Journalism – Level 3

RESEARCH & ADMIN ASSISTANT

CLEAR LAW SOLICITORS, OLD TRAFFORD | 11/2014 - 02/2015 - Temporary Role

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ESSEX: 2011

BA – Philosophy & Human Rights

NEWS ASSOCIATES MANCHESTER: 2015

Diploma in Journalism - Level 3

KNUTSFORD HIGH SCHOOL, ESSEX: 2001 - 2008

A / AS LEVELS English Language – A Philosophy and Ethics – B General English Literature – A

Studies – D

History A*

English Language & Literature – C Biology Chemistry - A Physics - B Chemistry (AS) - C French - B Biology - B

GCSEs Art & Design - C

Maths - A

OTHER EXPERIENCE

My previous experience includes interning as a Reporter, and I graduated with a degree in Philosophy and Human Rights. My hobbies include playing guitar and singing, as well as drawing, writing, and I was the President of the Judo club at university.

Growing up, my use of computers earned me a reputation within my family, and I naturally became the resident tech support. I remember my first time learning about how websites were put together; it was thanks to MySpace's use of HTML in profile design. My friends and I would find little bits to add to our profiles, changing the layout or colours manually, or with snippets we had found online. More recently, I have spent some time playing the Raspberry Pi computers, creating a Spotify player, and a retro gaming emulator.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.